{"Topic": "Computers", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "A computer virus normally attaches itself to another computer programme known as a", "op1": "Backdoor programme", "op2": "Target programme", "op3": "Trojan horse", "op4": "Host programme", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "One byte consists of", "op1": "four bits", "op2": "one bit", "op3": "ten bit", "op4": "eight bits", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The amount of time required by a storage device to retrieve data and programmes is its", "op1": "Retrieval speed", "op2": "Capacity", "op3": "Memory", "op4": "Access speed", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "ENIAC was", "op1": "an electronic computer", "op2": "an engine", "op3": "a memory device", "op4": "an electronic calculator"}, {"Question": "Which of these describes attempts by individuals to obtain confidential information from a computer user by falsifying their identity?", "op1": "Fishing", "op2": "Computer viruses", "op3": "Spyware", "op4": "Phishing", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The first computer made available for commercial use was", "op1": "MANIAC", "op2": "ENIAC", "op3": "UNIVAC", "op4": "EDSAC", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "A person who uses his or her expertise to gain access to other people's computers to get information illegally or do damage can be called a", "op1": "Hacker", "op2": "Spammer", "op3": "Analyst", "op4": "Programmer", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "A 32-bit word computer can access _____ bytes at a time.", "op1": "4", "op2": "8", "op3": "16", "op4": "32", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The process of transferring files from the Internet to your computer is called", "op1": "Downloading", "op2": "Uploading", "op3": "File Transfer Protocol", "op4": "Hypertext Transfer Protocol", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The ____ shows all the web sites any pages that you have visited one a period of time.", "op1": "Status bar", "op2": "Task bar", "op3": "History list", "op4": "Tool bar", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The language which provides basic building blocks for web pages is known as", "op1": "HTML", "op2": "C language", "op3": "Java", "op4": "Javascript", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In the URL, http//:www.leadthecompetition.in, the portion labelled http is the ____", "op1": "Host", "op2": "Domain name", "op3": "Protocol", "op4": "Top-level domain", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a read only memory storage device?", "op1": "Floppy Disk", "op2": "Hard Disk", "op3": "CDROM", "op4": "Flash Drive", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "A repair for a known software bug usually available at no charge on the internet is called a", "op1": "Patch", "op2": "Version", "op3": "Tutorial", "op4": "FAQ", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following connects the computer to a telephone line?", "op1": "Processor", "op2": "Modem", "op3": "USB Drive", "op4": "Multiplexer", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is an e-mail attachment?", "op1": "A receipt sent by the recipient", "op2": "A separate document from another programme sent along with an e-mail message", "op3": "A malicious parasite that feeds off of your message and destroys the contents", "op4": "A list of GC, or BCC, recipients", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "If a file has a '.bak' extension it refers usually to -", "op1": "Backup file", "op2": "Audio file", "op3": "Temporary file", "op4": "Deleted file", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The window which shows icons for things like the mouse, sound, and display is called", "op1": "My Computer", "op2": "Explorer", "op3": "Control Panel", "op4": "Taskbar", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What kind of file has an extension '.mpg'?Word Document fileSpreadsheet documentMovie fileImage fileAnswer (c).  20. Which of the following is not real security and privacy risks?HackersSpamVirusesIdentity theftAnswer (b).  21. Which of the following defines the ability to recover and read deleted or damaged files from a criminal\u2019s computer?RoboticsSimulationComputer forensicsAnimationAnswer (c).  22. The difference between people with internet access and those without it is known as theDigital divideInternet divideWeb divideBroadband divideAnswer (a).  23. The smallest unit in a digital system is abytebitwordcharacterAnswer (b).  24.Which of the following is a web browser?Macromedia FlashMicrosoft PowerpointNetscape NavigatorAdobe DreamweaverAnswer (c).  25. Junk e-mail is also called ____SpamSpoofSniffer scriptSpoolAnswer (a).  ", "op1": "Word Document file", "op2": "Spreadsheet document", "op3": "Movie file", "op4": "Image file", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not real security and privacy risks?", "op1": "Hackers", "op2": "Spam", "op3": "Viruses", "op4": "Identity theft", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following defines the ability to recover and read deleted or damaged files from a criminal\u2019s computer?", "op1": "Robotics", "op2": "Simulation", "op3": "Computer forensics", "op4": "Animation", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The difference between people with internet access and those without it is known as the", "op1": "Digital divide", "op2": "Internet divide", "op3": "Web divide", "op4": "Broadband divide", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The smallest unit in a digital system is a", "op1": "byte", "op2": "bit", "op3": "word", "op4": "character", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a web browser?", "op1": "Macromedia Flash", "op2": "Microsoft Powerpoint", "op3": "Netscape Navigator", "op4": "Adobe Dreamweaver", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following is the founder of Facebook?", "op1": "Tim Berners Lee", "op2": "Jimmy Wales", "op3": "Julian Assange", "op4": "Mark Zuckerburg", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which of the following areas, spreadsheet software is more useful?", "op1": "Psychology", "op2": "Publishing", "op3": "Statistics", "op4": "Message sending", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is windows explorer?", "op1": "A drive", "op2": "APC", "op3": "A web browser", "op4": "A file manager", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following terms refers to unwanted and unsolicited e-mails received by us?", "op1": "spam", "op2": "subscriptions", "op3": "rubbish", "op4": "trash", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "A Groupware is a", "op1": "Hardware", "op2": "Software", "op3": "Network", "op4": "Firmware", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "A DVD is An example of a/an", "op1": "Hard disk", "op2": "Optical disk", "op3": "Output device", "op4": "Solid state storage device", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "A word in a web page that, when clicked opens another document is called", "op1": "Anchor", "op2": "Hyperlink", "op3": "Preference", "op4": "URL", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the most commonly used operating system?", "op1": "Windows", "op2": "UNIX", "op3": "Mac OS", "op4": "Linux", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Windows 7, the operating system from Microsoft Corporation has ________ Indian languages fonts.", "op1": "14", "op2": "26", "op3": "37", "op4": "49", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "A megabyte is actually equal to ______ kilobytes", "op1": "100", "op2": "1000", "op3": "1024", "op4": "1028", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is an Indian social networking site launched by Patna-based brothers Nilay and Ankur Singh?", "op1": "Indiabook", "op2": "Jumpbook", "op3": "Kitabi Chehra", "op4": "Desibook", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following was referred to as a 'three-finger salute' by Microsoft founder Mr. Bill Gates?", "op1": "control - alt - delete buttons", "op2": "stand-by - turn-off - start options", "op3": "scroll-lock - num lock and print screen buttons", "op4": "control - shift - alt buttons", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the full form of GUI?", "op1": "Graphics User Instruction", "op2": "Graphical User Interface", "op3": "General User Intruction", "op4": "General User Interaction", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which command allows you to reduce fragments of file and optimize the performance of disk?", "op1": "Scandisk", "op2": "Diskcomp", "op3": "Chkdsk", "op4": "Defrag", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "A communication processor that connects dissimilar networks by providing the translation from one set of protocol to another is", "op1": "Bridge", "op2": "Gateway", "op3": "Router", "op4": "Modem", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What is a fraudulent practice of extracting details of someone's bank card or account illegally via phone known as?", "op1": "phising", "op2": "spamming", "op3": "vishing", "op4": "bombing", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In a Database Management System (DBMS), the content and the location of the data is defined by the -", "op1": "metadata", "op2": "subdata", "op3": "sequence data", "op4": "multi dimensional data", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the ascending order of data hierarchy?", "op1": "Bit - Byte - Record - Field - Database - File", "op2": "Byte - Bit - File - Record - Database - Field", "op3": "Bit - Byte - Field - Record - File - Database", "op4": "Field - Byte - Bit - Record - File - Database", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "A Computer executes Programs in the sequence of:", "op1": "Decode, Fetch, Execute", "op2": "Execute, Fetch, Decode", "op3": "Fetch, Decode, Execute", "op4": "Store, Fetch, Execute", "Answer": 1}]}